<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>The Deadman's site</title>
<link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/</link>
<atom:link href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<description>Just a website I'm making for fun</description>
<item>
  <title>Flexbox and more changes</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2019/06/flexbox-and-more-changes.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2019/06/flexbox-and-more-changes.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>So, just last week I was saying a bunch of changes I had made, well, this is not gonna be as long, it's just some little updates.</p>

    <h3>New layout (again)</h3>
    <div class="blog-post-picture">
      <picture>
        <source srcset="/images/webp/posts-flex-page.webp" type="image/webp" />
        <source srcset="/images/jpg/posts-flex-page.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
        <img src="/images/jpg/posts-flex-page.jpg" alt="A screenshot of the posts page" />
      </picture>
      <div class="blog-picture-text"><a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/about.html" target="_blank">CC BY-SA 4.0</a></div>
    </div>

    <p>Yes, as you see, and as you probably saw to see this article. A new tweak for the
    layout, on desktops, you get more space used which is pretty good, really. I'm not
    sure how I like how it messes a little bit with how linear it was but it works
    and it's still quite easy to manage.</p>

    <h3>Related pages</h3>
    <p>I'm not sure what to say, I'm putting articles at the bottom of articles so people
    can discover new content from other people or my older content. Kind of similar to webrings
    but well, more curated in a way.</p>

    <h3>Mistakes</h3>
    <p>I'm quite scared and stressed about this but I do want to let it out. It'll take time
    and courage but I'll do it.</p>

    <h3>More appropriate links</h3>
    <p>Old links will be broken, sorry about that but I think the new ones better fit the content.</p>

    <p>Anyways, I'll try to stop redesigning so much and creating so much meta content. Sorry.</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Time for some change!</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2019/06/time-for-some-change.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2019/06/time-for-some-change.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>So I've not updated this blog in a while but in the last few days I've updated it a bunch!
    So here's some of the key changes from this.</p>

    <h3>Biggest change probably : No more comments!</h3>

    <p>So you might've thought it was about toxicity in comments or something about
    the ethics of it... It wasn't used much either or well, I should say, I never saw it
    being used.</p>

    <div class="blog-post-picture">
      <picture>
        <source srcset="/images/webp/comments.webp" type="image/webp" />
        <source srcset="/images/jpg/comments.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
        <img src="/images/jpg/comments.jpg" alt="A screenshot of cloudflare saying that comment.sh is down." />
      </picture>
      <div class="blog-picture-text"><a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/about.html" target="_blank">CC BY-SA 4.0</a></div>
    </div>

    <p>But well, it's a lot simpler than that, the service seems to be no more.
    I contacted the admin and there was no response, it's possible that the email service is also dead but well,
    it's gone for now atleast.</p>

    <h3>Licensing</h3>
    <p>So I did quite a bit of changes relating to work licenses, I already had the code under AGPLv3 as per <a href="/posts/2018/05/this-blog-is-agplv3.html">my blog post</a>
    but well, I have more changes.</p>

    <h4>Proper license notice for artwork</h4>
    <p>Now all of the artwork I use has the license terms and a link to the source for attribution! The github also has LICENSES files
    to make this easier for those who are seeing from there. I'm pretty happy with how that looks too.</p>

    <h4>Licensing my text as CC BY-SA 4.0</h4>
    <p>Now all of the text is under CC BY-SA 4.0 which is noted at the end of each article
    so this change is pretty self-explanatory..</p>

    <h3>New styling</h3>

    <div class="blog-post-picture">
      <picture>
        <source srcset="/images/webp/posts-page.webp" type="image/webp" />
        <source srcset="/images/jpg/posts-page.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
        <img src="/images/jpg/posts-page.jpg" alt="A screenshot of the posts page" />
      </picture>
      <div class="blog-picture-text"><a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/about.html" target="_blank">CC BY-SA 4.0</a></div>
    </div>
    <div class="picture-description">
      <p>Just a screenshot of the page to show it off.</p>
    </div>

    <p>I've done some few changes with the design, <a href="/posts.html">the posts page</a> is more minimalist
    and more similar to the mobile view, I like it.</p>

    <p>As you may have seen too, there's a dark theme too! It works using "prefers-color-scheme: dark" which <a href="https://webkit.org/blog/8840/dark-mode-support-in-webkit/" target="_blank">Safari</a>,
    <a href="https://bugs.chromium.org/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=889087" target="_blank">Chromium</a> and <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1494034" target="_blank">Firefox</a> respect based
    on your operating system settings or an internal setting</p>

    <p>There's also new navigation changes which can be seen at the top for easier than
    before way to switch views.</p>

    <h3>Metadata changes</h3>
    <div class="blog-post-picture">
      <picture>
        <source srcset="/images/webp/discord_embed.webp" type="image/webp" />
        <source srcset="/images/jpg/discord_embed.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
        <img src="/images/jpg/discord_embed.jpg" alt="A screenshot of a discord embed of one of my articles" />
      </picture>
      <div class="blog-picture-text"><a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/about.html" target="_blank">CC BY-SA 4.0</a></div>
    </div>
    <div class="picture-description">
      <p>Just a screenshot of a discord embed.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="blog-post-picture">
      <picture>
        <source srcset="/images/webp/twit_embed.webp" type="image/webp" />
        <source srcset="/images/jpg/twit_embed.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
        <img src="/images/jpg/twit_embed.jpg" alt="A screenshot of a twitter embed of one of my articles" />
      </picture>
      <div class="blog-picture-text"><a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/about.html" target="_blank">CC BY-SA 4.0</a></div>
    </div>
    <div class="picture-description">
      <p>Just a screenshot of a twitter embed.</p>
    </div>
    <p>Now when websites need to embed the website, we give them the usual web author and description,
    we give OpenGraph metadata and Twitter metadata which should let them to have good embeds and previews for the content!</p>

    <h3>Switch to Webp</h3>
    <p>I put all the pictures from .pngs and .jpgs to .webps which reduced the size from there
    over five times (432kb from 2.9mb)!</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reponse to GNOME critique</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2019/05/response-to-gnome-critique.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2019/05/response-to-gnome-critique.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 2 May 2019 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>I'll be answering the points one at a time as a gnome user so strap on for the ride, it's
    gonna be a long one. I'd highly recommend reading their post first so you can see the points
    which I'm adressing.</p>

    <h3>1. A Desktop that does nothing</h3>
    <p>That's part of the design, get everything out of the way. That's also why the workplace
    switcher isn't shown unless you press the user key. Maximimize screen real estate while
    still offering the features in a coherent manner.</p>

    <h3>2. Barely functional status bar</h3>
    <p>Sound is the exception because most people will simply use the keyboard keys unlike
    Wi-Fi or Bluetooth where that's not an option? That makes sense to me, I'm not sure what's
    off about this</p>

    <h4>a. Connecting to a Wi-Fi network is too many steps</h4>
    <p>From my understanding, this is done to avoid having an overly long sub-menu but still
    being able to quickly change networks (as opposed to opening the settings app which would be more work)
    It's a compromise made by design</p>

    <h4>b. No battery percentage option</h4>
    <p>This entry is misleading at best, you yourself admit that the option exists in Gnome Tweaks
    I'll explain why Gnome Tweaks is a good thing later ;)</p>

    <h4>c. No app indicators</h4>
    <p>This one is a little more complicated to explain. It's a good thing. Bear with me now.</p>
    <p>First of all, the <b>old</b> format was the one supported by TopIcons, it's quite poor due
    to the API and so, they removed support for that old API.</p>
    <p>"Okay but I want them!" I hear you say, that's why Ubuntu made the extension with a newer
    and better API which people actually support unlike what you lead people to believe when you say
    "Even if a better implementation may exist, it needs to be understood and accepted that cross-platform apps are unlikely to create indicators specific to the Linux Desktop, a marketshare of less than 5%.".</p>
    <p>"Okay well, why isn't that in GNOME?", well, it's relatively new for one and well, it's
    more effort to maintain the more options you give but of course, that's entirely the reason why
    it's not done, it's also possibly because of design decisions</p>
    <p>And that's where you comment on the GNOME-styled "Fragments" torrent client come in, that's the design that
    GNOME seems to want, "if you want your program to run, you should leave it open", and you might say that's terrible but
    here's the thing, GNOME is a very keyboard-based (more on that in a second) and uses Workspaces quite heavily so what
    you'd do is.. use them to put background programs if you don't currently need them or they're done for a specific "work" environment.</p>
    <p>So about the keyboard oriented design of this anti-feature. What this effectively means is that you can use natural
    keyboard bindings to get to your application instead of using your cursor to get to the icon.</p>
    <p>As for the intrusivity of the notifications, I hear you, I'd personally want a do-not-disturb feature to block the peeking
    as Pop!_OS provides, I think that's the best way to go about this issue.</p>

    <h4>d. No suspend button</h4>
    <p>Yeah, that's not great design and should be fixed, I agree.</p>

    <h3>3. Deceiving app drawer</h3>
    <p>You bundled things together here but I'll try to stay coherent in my response. First of all, keyboard shortcuts should
    be known, they're all in the settings if it really bothered anyone to have to click the application drawer icon in the first
    place... It's really the first time I hear this.</p>
    <p>As for the truncated names, I don't really think this as an issue considering the icons are also shown but as you said, it's a
    WIP which will be done eventually for those that are bothered by it</p>
    <p>The folder issue is real, I'll give you that but software handling it after a little of grumble works relatively well I
    would say.</p>

    <h3>4. Unnecessary notifications</h3>
    <p>That's done by design, windows are not meant to grab focus on gnome automatically, this can be annoying if you start an
    application then it just decides "lol, you were doing something? Well, I don't care, focus on me" and so it tells you that the application
    has sucessfully loaded in instead, I would not expect this to change. Use the extension if you want to be annoyed</p>

    <h3>5. Barebones file manager</h3>
    <h4>a. Can’t create new document from the context menu</h4>
    <p>It's in the help documents, maybe use them. Although a default for a blank file might be useful. I'm not sure how
    you would want this to be more "intuitive"</p>
    <h4>b. Confusing action buttons</h4>
    <p>I think I'll be repeating myself more but it's by design, tooltips are not elegant and you misconceived the hamburger
    menu as a setting menu while it's an option menu since you wouldn't put 30 bajillion options in the titlebar, that would
    be a cursed sight.</p>

    <h4>c. Same icons for different file types</h4>
    <p>Can we not make an icon for literally every format on planet earth? Please. They're similar formats, let's use the
    same icon, spare my sanity.</p>

    <h4>d. Oh, the file picker!</h4>
    <p>Have you ever thought that GNOME devs aren't bothered by it and if people care so much about a stupid issue like that
    they could instead fix it rather than meme it? I think it's quite an hostile mentality to expect people to work on
    everything and then complain and meme the issue rather than trying to fix it.</p>

    <h4>e. Non-discoverable way to bookmark folders</h4>
    <p>Next thing you're gonna tell me that menubars are not intuitive and as per the issue you filed, we would like to not
    duplicate that UI since it's frankly not very useful to do so and just more clutter... and GNOME tries to avoid exactly that.</p>

    <h3>6. Document viewer (PDF reader) with no tabs!</h3>
    <p>The developer of the application doesn't want this by design. If you don't like it, there are other applications
    which you can use. Please don't force people to do things that they don't want because "People want it!". Thank you.</p>

    <h3>7. Two photo viewing apps</h3>
    <p>While yes, you could dislike that. There is a clear distinction between the two and maybe I don't want "GNOME Photos" to manage
    my photos but rather another photo manager but I still want a lightweight option like "Eye of Gnome" to view my pictures (which is what I do if you were wondering).</p>
    <p>It's kind of interesting how you fight to get more options unless when you personally find it inconvenient..</p>

    <h3>8. Can’t find my settings</h3>
    <p>I know I'll hate this part.. but here we go.</p>

    <h4>a. Undiscoverable settings</h4>
    <p>Uncommon things are put behind 3 dot menus, who would've thought, right?..</p>
    <p>Also, while you have ample of space, it's worth mentioning that most people can access more than 3 access points
    meaning there isn't as much place as you'd think.</p>

    <h4>b. Can’t set a custom wallpaper</h4>
    <p>Expect you can and you just said so.. sure, a file picker would be nice but what you're saying is <b>very</b> misleading</p>

    <h4>c. Tweaks app that shouldn’t exist</h4>
    <p>I knew this was gonna happen... why..</p>
    <p>Okay, so, yes, <b>some</b> options could be changed over. <b>However</b>, this is a design decision..
    So, we don't want the clusterfuck of options from KDE so we put it in another application so those things are still available
    while not overwhelming the user which uses the settings application.</p>
    <p>But there's also another thing to consider, some of those settings are not entirely safe to use so we might not want them
    to be as easy to access as all the other options to avoid the user breaking their system. Some options which could result in that
    include : Scaling, Themes, Extensions.</p>
    <p>TL;DR : It's a compromise between flexibility and stability</p>
    <p>Furthermore, gnome settings is more so DE-agnostic being that I could use all of the settings in there in another
    environment, while with Tweaks, that's not the case.</p>

    <h3>9. Software Center</h3>
    <p>These are just shown in the updates menu where you would expect them to be... Also, if they don't show up there,
    it's your distro's fault</p>

    <h3>Conclusion</h3>
    <p>Even though I appreciate the time you've taken to state your
    points, I highly disagree and hope you can understand my points. Thanks for reading.</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Crawling back to Github..</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/09/crawling-back-to-github.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/09/crawling-back-to-github.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>I'm really sad. My code contributions have been quite low and I haven't worked as much
    as I wish I did, my code's been relatively untouched in the last months even though
    I need to modify it. But I'm also sad that my switch to Gitlab has not been as smooth
    as I wish it had been.</p>

    <p>First of all, the most frustrating part is how Gitlab handles watching and the lack of
    notifications unlike Github. This makes me watch my repositories manually most of the time
    which is quite frustrating. I really hope they work on this.</p>

    <p>I would switch to something which does have notifications like for example
    <a href="https://gitbucket.github.io/">Gitbucket</a> but I have no hosting place to do this
    so it's an impossibility at the moment. Maybe somebody else can offer it to me until I can
    use a VPS of my own</p>

    <p>I really hate to do this but notifications is something I really need out of my
    git platform. *sighs*</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>This blog is AGPLv3!</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/05/this-blog-is-agplv3.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/05/this-blog-is-agplv3.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>This whole blog's source code is now licensed under AGPLv3, celebrate! Okay, the code is pretty crappy
    but that's another story, hopefully it improves. Feel free to contribute!</p>

    <div class="blog-post-picture">
      <picture>
        <source srcset="/images/webp/gitlab.webp" type="image/webp" />
        <source srcset="/images/jpg/gitlab.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
        <img src="/images/jpg/gitlab.jpg" alt="A screenshot of the gitlab repository" />
      </picture>
      <div class="blog-picture-text"><a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/about.html" target="_blank">CC BY-SA 4.0</a></div>
    </div>

    <p>I may have broken some things with some of the changes I did but I think it's okay. At least, when I tested
    locally, who knows what'll happen once this thing goes on Neocities. Hopefully nothing otherwise that'd suck.</p>

    <p>I'm still waiting for someone to actually comment on here which kind of stinks, I was hoping for people to do so!
    Who are those 1660 (at the time of this writing) people who saw this blog? What do they think? It really interests me.</p>

    <p>Anyhow, that's off-topic and so, I'll just end this blog post here. Oh, right! The source code is <a href="https://gitlab.com/Lionirdeadman/lionirdeadman.neocities.org">here</a>
    I may have a mirror on Github later, maybe, we'll see if anyone wants me to do so. Well, that's all I had to say, have a good day y'all!</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Comments on my blog!</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/05/comments-on-my-blog.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/05/comments-on-my-blog.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>Okay so I've been thinking about the best way for people reading my blog to contact me and I think I've found
    a solution which is pretty good.. comments! Okay, here's why that's a good way.</p>

    <h3>1. Control</h3>
    <p>With the comment system in place, I don't have a contact page but that's good, you'll just comment and put your email
    address and other ways I can contact you there and then I can contact you when I want, this means that I won't risk getting
    spammed as much.</p>

    <h3>2. Privacy</h3>
    <p>The messages will not be public until I approve them so if you give me your contact information inside the comment, I'll simply
    delete it and it'll never be seen by other people.</p>

    <h3>3. Just.. comments!</h3>
    <p>If you post a comment regarding the article / blog post, I'll approve it and people
    will be able to see it and reply to you. I think it'll be really cool to see what you all think of this and it won't
    feel like I'm talking to myself anymore, haha.</p>

    <p>Oh! I almost forgot, the javascript and third-party service provider will not be loaded until you click
    the "Show comments" button so you can still read it without a third-party snooping on you.</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Friendships and honesty.</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/05/friendships-and-honesty.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/05/friendships-and-honesty.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>I strongly believe that honesty is the foundation of any relationship. If you're not honest
    with the people you talk to, you're not yourself. You're simply protraying someone
    which you're not and therefore you're actually creating a relationship in which
    two people, whom they're not, are in a relationship.</p>

    <blockquote>"Your friendship is therefore simply an illusion."</blockquote>

    <p>You may say that your relationship is fine if you lie 'sometimes' but this gives precendence for future dishonesty.
    If you lie because of shame, guilt or even fear, this relationship is toxic because it's one in which you can't express
    yourself. You are scared of the person with whom you're supposedly friends with.</p>

    <p>And if you're scared of that person, why would you be with them in the first place?
    You should be able to tell them anything without fear of consequences.</p>

    <p>You may not want your friends to know certain things because you're not comfortable and I think that's perfectly normal but you
    shouldn't be hiding it, you should simply tell them you don't want to give them this information because you don't
    have that kind of relationship with them.</p>

    <p>I think I'm starting to go in circles so I'll just end this post here..
    Maybe I'm crazy to think this way, I'm not sure anymore..</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Why am I using Neocities?</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/04/why-neocities.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/2018/04/why-neocities.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>Well, for one, it's free. "Okay, and?", you may be saying. I don't have the burden of hosting.
    I can simply code away the html and not worry about anything else..</p>

    <blockquote>"This gives me freedom and peace of mind."</blockquote>

    <div class="blog-post-picture">
      <picture>
        <source srcset="/images/webp/neocities.webp" type="image/webp" />
        <source srcset="/images/jpg/neocities.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
        <img src="/images/jpg/neocities.jpg" alt="A screenshot of the neocities homepage" />
      </picture>
      <div class="blog-picture-text"><a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/about.html" target="_blank">CC BY-SA 4.0</a></div>
    </div>

    <div class="picture-description">
      <p> Just a screenshot of the neocities homepage because I can... </p>
    </div>

    <p>Not only that but since there's no database or anything, just static files.
    I've also further restricted myself by not using javascript (although that may change)</p>

    <p>Why? Because the web is bloated and it takes way too long to load most
    pages and they're just filled with ads, trackers, javascript and other crap.</p>

    <p>So I'm just gonna post from here from time to time some decently-sized posts..
    You can also subsribe to the <a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/atom.xml">rss</a> to see whenever I post something
    on here without making an account and stuff.</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
