<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>The Deadman's site</title>
<link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/</link>
<atom:link href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<description>Just a website I'm making for fun</description>
<item>
  <title>Crawling back to Github..</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/29-09-2018.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/29-09-2018.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>I'm really sad. My code contributions have been quite low and I haven't worked as much
    as I wish I did, my code's been relatively untouched in the last months even though
    I need to modify it. But I'm also sad that my switch to Gitlab has not been as smooth
    as I wish it had been.</p>

    <p>First of all, the most frustrating part is how Gitlab handles watching and the lack of
    notifications unlike Github. This makes me watch my repositories manually most of the time
    which is quite frustrating. I really hope they work on this.</p>

    <p>I would switch to something which does have notifications like for example 
    <a href=https://gitbucket.github.io/>Gitbucket</a> but I have no hosting place to do this
    so it's an impossibility at the moment. Maybe somebody else can offer it to me until I can
    use a VPS of my own</p>

    <p>I really hate to do this but notifications is something I really need out of my 
    git platform. *sighs*</p>

    <h5>Posted on Sep 29, 2018</h5>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>This blog is AGPLv3!</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/21-05-2018.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/21-05-2018.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>This whole blog's source code is now licensed under AGPLv3, celebrate! Okay, the code is pretty crappy
    but that's another story, hopefully it improves. Feel free to contribute!</p>

    <div class="blog-post-picture">
      <img src="../images/gitlab.png">
    </div>

    <p>I may have broken some things with some of the changes I did but I think it's okay. At least, when I tested
    locally, who knows what'll happen once this thing goes on Neocities. Hopefully nothing otherwise that'd suck.</p>

    <p>I'm still waiting for someone to actually comment on here which kind of stinks, I was hoping for people to do so!
    Who are those 1660 (at the time of this writing) people who saw this blog? What do they think? It really interests me.</p>

    <p>Anyhow, that's off-topic and so, I'll just end this blog post here. Oh, right! The source code is <a href="https://gitlab.com/Lionirdeadman/lionirdeadman.neocities.org">here</a>
    I may have a mirror on Github later, maybe, we'll see if anyone wants me to do so. Well, that's all I had to say, have a good day y'all!</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Comments on my blog!</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/16-05-2018.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/16-05-2018.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>Okay so I've been thinking about the best way for people reading my blog to contact me and I think I've found
    a solution which is pretty good.. comments! Okay, here's why that's a good way.</p>

    <h3>1. Control</h3>
    <p>With the comment system in place, I don't have a contact page but that's good, you'll just comment and put your email
    address and other ways I can contact you there and then I can contact you when I want, this means that I won't risk getting
    spammed as much.</p>

    <h3>2. Privacy</h3>
    <p>The messages will not be public until I approve them so if you give me your contact information inside the comment, I'll simply
    delete it and it'll never be seen by other people.</p>

    <h3>3. Just.. comments!</h3>
    <p>If you post a comment regarding the article / blog post, I'll approve it and people
    will be able to see it and reply to you. I think it'll be really cool to see what you all think of this and it won't
    feel like I'm talking to myself anymore, haha.</p>

    <p>Oh! I almost forgot, the javascript and third-party service provider will not be loaded until you click
    the "Show comments" button so you can still read it without a third-party snooping on you.</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Friendships and honesty.</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/14-05-2018.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/14-05-2018.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>I strongly believe that honesty is the foundation of any relationship. If you're not honest
    with the people you talk to, you're not yourself. You're simply protraying someone
    which you're not and therefore you're actually creating a relationship in which
    two people, whom they're not, are in a relationship.</p>

    <blockquote>"Your friendship is therefore simply an illusion."</blockquote>

    <p>You may say that your relationship is fine if you lie 'sometimes' but this gives precendence for future dishonesty.
    If you lie because of shame, guilt or even fear, this relationship is toxic because it's one in which you can't express
    yourself. You are scared of the person with whom you're supposedly friends with.</p>

    <p>And if you're scared of that person, why would you be with them in the first place?
    You should be able to tell them anything without fear of consequences.</p>

    <p>You may not want your friends to know certain things because you're not comfortable and I think that's perfectly normal but you
    shouldn't be hiding it, you should simply tell them you don't want to give them this information because you don't
    have that kind of relationship with them.</p>

    <p>I think I'm starting to go in circles so I'll just end this post here..
    Maybe I'm crazy to think this way, I'm not sure anymore..</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Why am I using Neocities?</title>
  <link>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/27-04-2018.html</link>
  <guid>https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/posts/27-04-2018.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
  <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>Well, for one, it's free. "Okay, and?", you may be saying. I don't have the burden of hosting.
    I can simply code away the html and not worry about anything else..</p>

    <blockquote>"This gives me freedom and peace of mind."</blockquote>

    <div class="picture-description">
    <img src="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/images/neocities.png"></label>
    </div>

    <div class="picture-description">
      <p> Just a screenshot of the neocities homepage because I can... </p>
    </div>

    <p>Not only that but since there's no database or anything, just static files.
    I've also further restricted myself by not using javascript (although that may change)</p>

    <p>Why? Because the web is bloated and it takes way too long to load most
    pages and they're just filled with ads, trackers, javascript and other crap.</p>

    <p>So I'm just gonna post from here from time to time some decently-sized posts..
    You can also subsribe to the <a href="https://lionirdeadman.neocities.org/atom.xml">rss</a> to see whenever I post something
    on here without making an account and stuff.</p>
  ]]>
  </description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
